Hello.
Welcome back.
In this lesson, we are going to see how to figure out what you are to work with.
The DMA.
So let's get started.
I've created a new project of Klett all pan out.
We're going to use our user, Toine, in this example in loop buck mode.
And what I mean by loop back is we're going to connect the T X and our X line and it sends you see that
one is better suited for this experiment, especially when you have the new glue board where they use
that to is use.
That's your debugger.
So I'm going to come to my connectivity.
And then you saw one over here and I'm going to select it to act.
Also, you are two, which is the asynchronous mode.
And then down.
So like this for me.
And then I'll go to clock configuration.
Like I said, my clock configuration will always set it to sixteen 16.
Isolate H.S. I hear.
And then this becomes 16 and I'm going to set this to 16 as well.
Oh, hit enter.
Right.
So we can go ahead to configure the, um, the you.
I'll come to Piñon configuration and then the systems view and then I'll click on you saw one we use
and just use one in this experimental.
Click here to open it up.
Let's see.
You has to be opened.
Okay.
And then we don't need NVC interrupt here so I'll leave that.
But DMA certains.
That's what we need.
So pull this up here and then I'll click to add.
And then a dropdown comes over here and also liked you saw one our X and NDR X the stream.
I can choose it at DMA stream to or stream five.
I'll keep this the same.
And then this is the reception.
So this is to receive data.
The direction is from peripheral to memory.
And we know that course you are receiving from the pen and storing it in memory and then you might use
it for something after you start it.
And the priority.
We don't care much about that.
And then we can add another DMA stream for the T x.
Also like this and this.
Defaults to stream seven.
And then this one T X is from memory to peripheral.
Because you write something and then you transmit over the peripheral line.
So that's the direction.
Right.
So it's looking good so far.
So now we can go ahead and generate the project.
A click over here.
I'll give it a name.
You art DMA.
I'll call this you Art.
You got on the school, DME, and then also led a toolchain, which is the SDM 32 QAD E and then click
here to generate the code.
So there's a project of clean up a bit of the comment.
This is very similar to our You Art Project standard.
You are just that we've got a DMA initialized here as well.
And then when you go to the the M, the UT in its function, it looks exactly the same way, apart from
a line that links that DMA and the You OTS together to show that we are using DME in this project.
So yeah, you can take a look at the M, the function is generated and if you want to know them step
by step, you can always refer to the m the whole user guide that we downloaded earlier.
So let's get started.
Remember, whenever you are using the DMA, the DMA uses the callback of the particle out here for your
use.
So whatever the callback function is for ADC is or time is when you are using ADC with DME.
Your callback will be the ADC conversion complete callback.
And that is where you do your code.
When Aboudi conversion complete occurs in the same instance while you are, the callback will be exactly
the same callbacks that we used in the previous you.
The project, which is the um, the you ot transfer a complete callback as well as the you are to receive
complete callback.
So I'm going to copy these callback functions from our previous project from specificly I y you interrupt
a project so I'll come to the you to interrupt a project over here.
We created a callback.
We had the um u r t x complete callback in Eriks.
I'm just going to copy them Coskata.
Same just at this time.
The trons added the transaction is going on with the DME rather than using the interruptive lines.
OK.
So then I'm going to bring our buffs as well, going to Koppio ATX and our X buffer and then we have
our our X content six counts.
I'm going to copy all of that.
It's exactly the same.
And then pasted in the one knew me and would see Father Y here and then.
Now I'll close the old one.
Okay.
The only difference over here is when we are going to call the receive and transmit function in the
interrupt example, we said how you are to receive on this call 84 interrupt.
This time we have to see how you are to receive DMA.
And we do the same for the, um, the transmit.
So come down here and then I'll see how underscore you at.
Unaskable receive an escort DMA, and then the first argument is the you are Tando, which is each U
out one.
The second argument is the M the buffer, which is the R X buffer.
And then the last argument is the size.
And then we do the same for transmit all on a score, you add on a school transmit underscore DMA.
The first SDM, Hondo H u r to one and then the puffer, which is the T X puffer.
And then the size like this.
OK.
And remember, this is still the loop buck mode or what I've been by loop loop buck mode is that we
have connected a jumper wire to our T X and our X line, which is P, A 10 and P nine, so that we can
just see that we received the data.
Right.
OK, click over here to build the project.
It's built successfully.
Click here for Debug.
No debugger has open.
Come to live expression.
I remove all of this, which belongs to the previous project room or and I'm going to add our our X
buffer to make sure to verify that we receive what we say and controversy out of here.
And then we can order our X counter as well.
And then I'm going to come over here and then put a break point in my wall, one loop by clicking here
like this.
Okay, then I'm going to click here to run and then click again.
You can see our X counter is one.
And when we check, we've received the data that we put in the transmitter buffer.
So this is you utter with DME and you can use the same method to transmit the data to view on your computer.
You can initialize the you out with DME and use your you you add.
Which is connected to the virtual comports and use the trout term, which is the serial program to view
it.
This or the rest.
If you have any questions, just let me know and I'll see you later.
Have a nice day.